# Doug Murphy

dougmurphy34@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

I love making big changes to small companies. I'm passionate about computer technology, green energy, and doing well while doing good. I see every job as a puzzle with an optimal solution to be discovered. I only work in places where I perceive social good in the business' end goal.

Though software creation has been the focus of my 15-year career, I've worked in a multitude of other roles and industries. My responsibilities have included collective bargaining, payroll, hiring, sales, marketing and manufacturing. I've worked comfortably in private industry, government, and military settings, with companies as small as two employees and as large as tens of thousands. My adaptability is my greatest professional asset.

#### SKILLS

- Microsoft SQL Server
- JavaScript
- Agile Methodologies
- Python

- NET
- Software Project Management
- HTML5
- Start-ups

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **Floodbat Creative**

09 / 2012 - Present

Co-Founder

Formed game design company to design, manufacture, market, and distribute tabletop games. Successfully Kickstarted and produced Weather Wars, a family card game, which is currently available at www.floodbat.com or on Amazon. Developed iOS mobile app Daily Music Dose, currently available on the Apple App Store. Android release anticipated Q1 2015.

# The Scripps Research Institute

08 / 2014 - 09 / 2014

Developer (contract)

Developed a citizen science game, modeled on Google Image Labeler (ESP), to classify scientific abstracts and generate patterns that would form the basis of an artificial intelligence tool to perform this process in the future. Code was written in Python, Django, and HTML5 in a Linux environment.

## UserTesting

01 / 2012 - 08 / 2014

**Usability Analyst** 

Provide clients with detailed feedback on usability, design and performance of web sites and mobile applications.

# **World Travel**

08 / 2011 - 08 / 2012

on Sabbatical

Sabbatical, living on six continents and developing ideas which became the foundation of Floodbat Creative.

# Helix Charter High School

Manager, Business and Information Services

Rebuilt delivery of business and IT services, including payroll, purchasing, accounting, financial reporting, computer support, network infrastructure, and data systems.

- Cut business office costs 30% while improving performance.
- Reduced Information Technology staff size 33% while improving response times.
- Built collaborative budget to improve student achievement while funding decreased 30%.
- Deployed Edupoint Genesis data system to unify all school data on a single system, and provided roles-based access and training to all staff, students, and parents.

## Innova Systems International, LLC

01 / 2002 - 12 / 2006

Software Development Manager

Developed, and later managed development of, web-based data driven software applications for U.S. Navy. Responsible for full product cycle, including requirements gathering, design, development, testing, and deployment.

- Implement agile/SCRUM methodology with biweekly deployment to meet changing customer demands.
- Effectively managed bi-coastal multidisciplinary team through brief daily teleconferences and digital task management tools VersionOne and Microsoft Project
- ASP.NET, SQL, VB/COM+ development.

## Veritas Medicine

01 / 2000 - 09 / 2001

Senior Web Developer

Developed online clinical trial matching algorithm as 7th employee of start-up venture.

- Developed ColdFusion middleware, Oracle backend, DHTML interfaces, and custom content management system.
- Deployed to Solaris(UNIX)/Apache servers with full replication

## Deloitte

06 / 1999 - 01 / 2000

Systems Analyst

SAP implementation analyst, certified in Controlling module.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Boston College**

1995 - 1999

B.S. with honors, Business Administration

Shaw Leadership Program, Wallace E. Carroll School of Management Honors Program

#### San Diego State University-California State University

2009 - 2010

Certification, Green Energy Management

#### **INTERESTS**

Data visualization, sustainability, acoustic guitar, games of all types